<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloth | QINGYANG TAN</title>
    <link>/tags/cloth/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/cloth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cloth</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Qingyang Tan</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Cloth</title>
      <link>/tags/cloth/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear Subspace Cloth Simulation</title>
      <link>/project/828x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/828x/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Qingyang Tan (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:qytan@cs.umd.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;qytan@cs.umd.edu&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we want to build a cloth simulator in a nonlinear subspace to reduce the search space. We leverage the graph-based convolutional neural network (GCNN) with a physical-inspired loss term to build an embedding network for cloth models. We then use mass-spring systems or finite-element method (FEM) to model the cloth energy and build a simulator based on the nonlinear embedded space. We show that using the proposed method can better capture cloth deformation and generalize on new control information well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloth simulation has applications in different areas, including animation, robotic control, gaming. Usually, the cloth is modeled as a 2D thin-shell object in a 3D space and represented by a high-resolution mesh. Many techniques have been developed to simulate the deformation of cloth in this mesh-based representation, including the mass-spring systems [1], the finite-element method [2]. However, the complexity of these methods depends on the number of degrees of freedoms (DOF), vary from $\mathcal{O}(n^{1.5})$ to $\mathcal{O}(n^{3})$. It would be hard to deploy high-resolution cloth simulation on devices with limited computation resources, e.g., cell phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data-driven methods have been proposed to accelerate the simulation process. These kinds of methods leverage the results from pre-computation to accelerate run-time simulation process. Previous works including non-learning methods, such as motion graph [3], and learning-based methods, such as subspace simulation [4, 5] and frame predictor [6, 7]. However, previous methods may suffer from loss of details or freedom of new control information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our project, we propose to combine GCNN based neural network embedding [8] and subspace integration to capture more details of cloth deformation while allowing full freedom to control the cloth simulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will briefly discuss previous works in this section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motion Graph&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subspace Integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frame Predictor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposed-method&#34;&gt;Proposed Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;experimental-results&#34;&gt;Experimental Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] K.-J. Choi and H.-S. Ko, “Stable but responsive cloth,” in SIGGRAPH 2002.&lt;br /&gt;
[2] R. Narain, A. Samii, and J. F. O’Brien, “Adaptive anisotropic remeshing for cloth simulation,”  ACM TOG, 2002.&lt;br /&gt;
[3] D. Kim, W. Koh, R. Narain, K. Fatahalian, A. Treuille, and J. F. O’Brien, “Near-exhaustive precomputation of secondary cloth effects,” ACM TOG, 2013.&lt;br /&gt;
[4] J. Barbič and D. L. James, “Real-time subspace integration for st. venant-kirchhoff deformable models,” ACM TOG, 2005.&lt;br /&gt;
[5] L. Fulton, V. Modi, D. Duvenaud, D. I. W. Levin, and A. Jacobson, “Latent-space dynamics for reduced deformable simulation,” Computer Graphics Forum, 2019.&lt;br /&gt;
[6] E. De Aguiar, L. Sigal, A. Treuille, and J. K. Hodgins, “Stable spaces for real-time clothing,” ACM TOG, 2010.&lt;br /&gt;
[7] D. Holden, B. C. Duong, S. Datta, and D. Nowrouzezahrai, “Subspace neural physics: fast data-driven interactive simulation,” in Proceedings of the 18th annual ACM SIGGRAPH/Eurographics Symposium on Computer Animation. ACM, 2019.&lt;br /&gt;
[8] Q. Tan, Z. Pan, L. Gao, and D. Manocha, “Realtime simulation of thin-shell deformable materials using cnn-based mesh embedding,” arXiv preprint arXiv:1909.12354, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new control ours

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b_Agzln2qWw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new control predictor

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ckX0NKs-uIg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hole

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6IoxsE7JdVE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fem

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tE4UZ3trZBA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realtime Simulation of Thin-Shell Deformable Materials using CNN-Based Mesh Embedding</title>
      <link>/publication/cloth_embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/cloth_embedding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
